Chillum Heights Citizens' Association 042
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Chillum Heights Citizens' Association Records
1894-1989
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Chillum Heights Citizens' Association
042
1.5 Linear feet
4 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Administrative Materials, 1895-1964 Series 2: Correspondence and Minutes, 1938-1962 Series 3: Topics, 1951-1963
Biographical / Historical
The Chillum Heights Citizens' Association was known as the Citizens Association of Rock Creek Church Road and Vicinity when organized in April 1894. A few months later, the name was changed to Woodburn Citizens' Association and finally to the Chillum Heights Citizens' Association. Throughout the Association's history members advocated for neighborhood safety, education, and city projects affecting residents of Chillum Heights. At its peak of organization the Association included committees on various topics that advocated for Chillum Heights throughout the District.
Custodial History
Donor unknown.
Related Materials
Federation of Citizens Associations of the District of Columbia Records (028) https://washingtoniana.dclibrary.org/repositories/2/resources/967
Scope and Contents
Collection contains meeting minutes, correspondence, financial materials, membership lists, and clippings regarding the activities of the Chillum Heights Citizens' Association. Collection also includes topical files on such subjects as D.C. Home Rule and suffrage, juvenile delinquency, crime, civil rights, racism, D.C. budgets, the Rock Creek expressway; as well as items from the Federation of Citizens Association and Neighbors Inc. Folders are arranged into three series: administrative materials; correspondence and minutes; and topics. The folders in the administrative and topical series are arranged alphabetically and folders in the correspondence/ minutes series are arranged chronologically.
Neighborhoods; Citizens' Associations; Associations, institutions, etc; Fort Totten (Washington, D.C.); Organizational Records; Correspondence; Minutes (Records); Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc); Community organization
- Series 1: Administrative Materials, 1895-1964
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1895 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitution/By-laws/amendments, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1950-1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Community map, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - D.C. organizations, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Federation of Citizens Association, 1910-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Federation of Citizens Association newsletter, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Highway clippings, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Membership list, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Membership roll, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 1894-1899 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Neighbors Inc., 1961-1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes and meeting procedures, September 1945-October 1946 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Neighborhood associations, 1956-1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Proclamations and remarks regarding the Charles Langley Bridge, Aug. 7 1946 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Rockcreek Expressway, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Treasure's reports, 1929-1938 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Series 2: Correspondence and Minutes, 1938-1962
  - Correspondence, 1938-1940 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and minutes, 1941-1944 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and minutes, 1946-1949 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1948-1960 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence and minutes, 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, October 1952-May 1953 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, July 1953-June 1954 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, September 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and minutes, 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence and minutes, 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Series 3: Topics, 1951-1963
  - Civic Defense, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Civil Rights and racism, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Communism, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Crime, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - D.C. budget, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Education, 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Health care, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Home rule and suffrage, 1954-1963 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Housing, 1952-1953 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Juvenile delinquency, 1960s (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Letter control, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Media, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Public Utilities, 1952-1954 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Recreation, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Traffic, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Urban renewal, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Washington Community Chest, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Youth issues, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Zoning, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 19)